Thomas N. Stevens papers, 1914-1964
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Thomas N. Stevens papers, 1914-1964
AZ 150
Stevens, Thomas N.
Correspondence, field surveys, legal and financial records pertaining to work with U.S. General Land Office, various mining companies, and individuals concerning land surveys to be used chiefly in patenting mining claims. Companies included are Amado Mines, Baca Float Ranch, Phelps Dodge Corporation, Morning Glory Mining Company, and Rancho del Lago. Also includes material concerning Tucson properties and landscaping.
1.2 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Stevens was a mineral surveyor in Tucson, Arizona.
Organization
This collection is organized into two series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1914-1964
Series II: Other Materials, 1920-1939
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, field surveys, legal and financial records pertaining to work with U.S. General Land Office, various mining companies, and individuals concerning land surveys to be used chiefly in patenting mining claims. Companies included are Amado Mines, Baca Float Ranch, Phelps Dodge Corporation, Morning Glory Mining Company, and Rancho del Lago. Also includes material concerning Tucson properties and landscaping.
Access Terms
United States. -- Surveyor General
Amado Mines
Baca Float Ranch
Phelps Dodge Corporation
Morning Glory Mining Company
United States -- General Land Office
Rancho del Lago
Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona
Real property -- Arizona -- Tucson
Correspondence
Surveys
Photographs
Related Material
Maps received with the collection were cataloged separately.
Container List
- Series I: Correspsondence, 1914-1964
  - Correspondence: General. 1917-1940, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence: Miscellaneous Professional (engineering societies, politics, personnel applications). 1923-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Amado Mines, Inc. 1929-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Baca Float Ranch, Inc. 1924-1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Phelps Dodge Corporation. 1924-1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: U.S. Surveyor General & General Land Office. 1914-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence: Equipment and Supplies. 1925-1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Investments (Colonial bond & Share Corp., Natinal Bond & Mortgage Co. of Illinois, U.S. Mortgage Bond Company of Detroit, Greenback Mining Company, Intermountain Building & Loan Assoc., Rio Grand Oil Company). 1925-1929 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Family, Miscellaneous Personal, Automobile. 1918-1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series II: Other Materials, 1920-1939
  - Morning Glory Mining Company (correspondence, maps, blue prints, photographs, ore settlements, assay reports). 1920-1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Rancho del Lago (correspondence, survey notes, blueprints). 1931-1937 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Property in Tucson (correspondence, legal papers, blueprints of houses in the Catalina foothills, Fairmont, Buell's, Palo Verde, Rincon Hights, and Williams Additions). 1924-1939 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Landscaping (general correspondence, material relating to landscapinging course.) 1928-1933 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Arizona State Board of Registration. 1924-1939 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Arizona State Water Commissioner, 1921-1936 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Financial Records (bank records, taxes, insurance and bills for a 1955 map of Tucson prepared by T.N. Stevens and Associates). 1924-1938, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Legal Papers. No Date (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Estate of Sarah (Stevens) Hiskey (sister of T.N. Stevens). 1940-1945 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Field Surveys (drawings). No Date (Box 3, Folder 10)